

28A Daventry St, Waterview, Auckland 1026

Mobile: 021 08899356 mrfuyuan@gmail.com

https://mrfu.me/ https://github.com/mrfufufu

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I had over four years' work experience of Android development, also familiar with iOS platform and Web platform; one year C# (WinForm) work experience. I am currently studying Graduate Diploma in Computing at Unitec. I have a blogging site about technologies, which recorded some of my development experiences. I am competent in programming practice and passionate on new technologies.

### **SKILLS & PROFILE**

- Good understanding of mobile application development, both Android and iOS.
- Familiar with Java, Kotlin, C#, Swift, HTML5, JavaScript.
- Solid knowledge of REST API design, Git and Subversion.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Full of framework and component implementation experience.
- Experience in project structure and Android/iOS Design standard.
- Continuously discover, evaluate and implement new technologies to maximise development efficiency.
- Technology sharing[1] [2] [3], and Open Source Code.

## **EDUCATION**

Graduate Diploma in Computing (Software Development) 2017 – 2018 (expected)

United Institute of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand

Bachelor of Engineering (Communication Engineering) 2009 – 2013

Zhijiang College of Zhejiang University of Technology, Hangzhou, China

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Android Developer (Team leader)

July 2014 - July 2017

Hangzhou Taofenba Network Technology Co.,Ltd.

China

- Designed and built applications for the Android platform: Xingxing and Haihu apps.
- Mainly focus on Android platform, but also work on HTML5 and iOS platform.

Android/C# (WinForm) Developer (Junior)

April 2013 - June 2014

Hangzhou Enjoyor Wise Information Technology of 120 group Co., Ltd.

China

 Developed E-Health(App) based on Windows platform (WinForm) and an Android Application.

### **PROJECTS**

#### 1. Card Diary for iOS (v2.0)

September 2017 - Now

It is a diary app. Card diary is a perfect place for you to think, feel, discover, expand, remember, and dream. A South Korean designer and I made a team to develop this app on iOS. It is now available in the App Store.

It uses Core Data to store diaries data in local and using iCloud to store diaries data on Cloud instead of writing a server-side code, so that I can focus on the client-side.

Website: <a href="https://inkdiary.me/">https://inkdiary.me/</a>

#### 2. Haihu for Android

July 2015 - July 2017

It is a shopping app. Data of products was retrieved from outbound websites (amazon.com, amazon.co.jp, 6pm.com etc.). We used the Spider (Web Crawler) to get products information which are shown on our app. Users buy products through Alipay (a Chinese paypal) instead of VISA or MasterCard (Alipay is overwhelmingly used in China).

As the Android team leader, I was responsible for

- The development and maintenance of the Android development platform\*.
- · Designed REST API for mobile and server.
- Designed the payment system for both Android and iOS apps.
- · Supervised junior team members.
- Timely and quality delivery of Android application.
- Managed Android team and drove efficient integration of development activities within the overall product delivery lifecycle.

#### 3. Xingxing for Android

July 2014 - June 2015

Daily Active Users: 200 thousand (peak)

Download Users: more than 5 million

It is an alarm clock app, by which users can wake people up through videos or voices.

I was responsible for

- Developed fundamental modules\*(image/caching/networking), social modules(chat/social update/fans/follows).
- · Released new versions.
- · Monitored feedbacks and crash reports.
- Designed REST API for mobiles and servers.

\*All of these modules were implemented by ourselves, of which the Open Source Code was released in my GitHub[1] [2] [3].

<sup>\*</sup>Using Glide, RxJava, Retrofit, Otto etc to construct our app's fundamental modules.

### 4. E-health for WinForm and Android

April 2013 - June 2014

This app is an outpatient infusion management system. It makes nurses easier to get the outpatients infusion information and increases their work efficiency.

I was responsible for the WinForm software on Windows, application on Windows Mobile and Android.

# **INTERESTS**

In my spare time, I enjoy running marathon and have completed four times so far. I am also a fan of RC Helicopter and drones. I am open-minded and like to give anything a go.

## **REFERENCES**

Available on request.